<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Political overview on Exploring the Cold War</title>
    <link>/next/political/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Political overview on Exploring the Cold War</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Mar 2018 01:09:39 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/next/political/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Berlin wall and reunification</title>
      <link>/next/political/berlin-wall/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 00:31:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/next/political/berlin-wall/</guid>
      <description>After the war: After World War II Germany was divided into four occupation zones. There was a British, a French and an American part in the west and a Soviet part in the east. In 1949 the western occupation zones were merged to the Federal Republic of Germany (FRG). In the same year the USSR founded the German Democratic Republic (GDR) in the east of Germany.
The western part of Germany had a great development during the 1950s and 1960s known as &amp;quot;Wirtschaftswunder&amp;quot; (economic miracle).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cuba</title>
      <link>/next/political/cuba/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 00:31:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/next/political/cuba/</guid>
      <description>After overthrowing Fulgencio Batista in 1959, Fidel Castro became the leader of Cuba. The new-created government proclaimed land reform and nationalized American possession – banks, mines, &amp;hellip; Because of this, USA stopped the business with Cuba. After that, Cuba asked USSR for economic and military help. USA didn’t like the good relationship between Cuba and USSR and increasing communism in Cuba therefore USA wanted to overthrow Castro.
 April 17, 1961 - more than 1400 Cuban exiles supported by CIA, landed on the beach Playa Girón.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Korean War</title>
      <link>/next/political/korea/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 00:31:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/next/political/korea/</guid>
      <description>Korea passed through a difficult situation between 1945 to 1949: two places were separated by the 38th parallel and then were occupied, the north by the Soviets and the south by the north Americans. With the confidence of having a USSR backrest and with the armed support of Mao Zedong, the Chinese leader, the North Korean communist Kim Il Sung, attacked the south area directed by the nationalist Syngman Rhee and he seized Seoul in 1950.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Latin America and Africa in the Cold War</title>
      <link>/next/political/africa/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 00:31:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/next/political/africa/</guid>
      <description>###Crisis of the Congo
The Congo Crisis was a period of political conflict in the Republic of Congo (today D.R. of Congo) in the timespan between 1960 – 1965. It was not only a civil war but also a proxy conflict of the Cold War, involving the Soviet Union and the UN/USA. The region was especially interesting for the two superpowers because it was very rich in natural resources such as Uranium.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uprising in Hungary, Czechoslovakia &amp; Poland</title>
      <link>/next/political/uprising/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 00:31:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/next/political/uprising/</guid>
      <description>###Uprisings in Czechoslovakia
Czechoslovakia was a part of the Soviet block from 1948 to 1989. The rule of the Communist party started with the Victorious February (1948) and end Velvet Revolution (November 1989).
{{ }} {{ &amp;lt; /image &amp;gt;}}
In the first election (May 26, 1946) the Communist party won and achieved the majority in parliament. Moreover, they also completely controlled the police. In protest most non-communist politicians resigned including president Beneš (February 20, 1948), Gottwald took his place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vietnam</title>
      <link>/next/political/vietnam/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Mar 2018 00:31:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/next/political/vietnam/</guid>
      <description>credit: https://fontawesome.comlicense: https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/ The Vietnam War was a long, costly and divisive conflict that pitted the communist government of North Vietnam against South Vietnam and its principal ally, the United States. The conflict was intensified by the ongoing Cold War between the United States and the Soviet Union. More than 3 million people (including over 58,000 Americans) were killed in the Vietnam War, and more than half of the dead were Vietnamese civilians.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>