<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Exploring the Cold War</title>
    <link>/article/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Exploring the Cold War</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 23:47:31 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/article/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Espionage</title>
      <link>/article/social/espionage/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 23:47:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/article/social/espionage/</guid>
      <description>The Cold War is often considered the golden age of espionage, a time when the United States and Soviet Union used all available tools to uncover each other’s secrets by operating with great secrecy and living double lives so they could infiltrate enemy governments. They certainly spent large amounts of money recruiting, training and utfitting spies and agents. The purpose of espionage was to collect information about the enemy, their army and technical abilities, their actions and intentions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freedom</title>
      <link>/article/social/freedom/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 23:47:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/article/social/freedom/</guid>
      <description>These are things which were restricted by communists:
 People could not express their opinion, if it was not identical with the opinion of communists Religious observance; believers were at a disadvantage Restriction of culture (theatres, films, art, music&amp;hellip;) Travelling Voting Assembly   Picture 1 (Source    )  The right to your own opinion When a person expressed his/her opinion and it was not identical with the opinion of the communist regime,the person could be pursued, put in prison or he/she was kicked out from his job.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Living Under Communism</title>
      <link>/article/social/livingundercommunism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 23:47:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/article/social/livingundercommunism/</guid>
      <description>Everyday life under communism in general Those who did not comply with socialism were not only interrogated, intimidated and put under surveillance but also subject to house searches, during which the Secret Police invaded citizens’ privacy while searching for illegal literature. Bribes abounded; the presence of bugs in homes prevented people from speaking openly; there were long lines at the shops; people were imprisoned for filing complaints or signing petitions. Furthermore, the rich turned poor as owners of extravagant housing were given new accommodation in the country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Berlin wall and reunification</title>
      <link>/article/political/berlin-wall/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 00:31:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/article/political/berlin-wall/</guid>
      <description>After the war: After World War II Germany was divided into four occupation zones. There was a joint British, French and an American zone in the west and a Soviet zone in the east. In 1949 the western occupation zones were merged into the Federal Republic of Germany (FRG). In the same year the USSR founded the German Democratic Republic (GDR) in the east of Germany.
In the western part of Germany there was a great development during the 1950s and 1960s known as &amp;quot;Wirtschaftswunder&amp;quot; (economic miracle).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Counter culture</title>
      <link>/article/social/counterculture/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 00:31:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/article/social/counterculture/</guid>
      <description>Vietnam became important to the Eastern and western blocs, the east wanted to win more communist satellite states and the west feared a communist revolt. The US supported South Vietnam with equipment and advise. This proxy war, which was typical of the Cold War, became almost like a conflict between the Soviet Union and US. Images and news from the war, for example the “Napalm Girl”, could now be seen on televisions across the world, they shocked people and many became opposed to what was happening.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cuba</title>
      <link>/article/political/cuba/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 00:31:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/article/political/cuba/</guid>
      <description>After overthrowing Fulgencio Batista in 1959, Fidel Castro became the leader of Cuba. The new-created government proclaimed land reform and nationalized American possession – banks, mines, &amp;hellip; Because of this, USA stopped the business with Cuba. After that, Cuba asked USSR for economic and military help. USA didn’t like the good relationship between Cuba and USSR and increasing communism in Cuba therefore USA wanted to overthrow Castro.
 April 17, 1961 - more than 1400 Cuban exiles supported by CIA, landed on the beach Playa Girón.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Korean War</title>
      <link>/article/political/korea/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 00:31:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/article/political/korea/</guid>
      <description>Korea passed through a difficult situation between 1945 to 1949: two places were separated by the 38th parallel and then were occupied, the north by the Soviets and the south by the north Americans. With the confidence of having a USSR backrest and with the armed support of Mao Zedong, the Chinese leader, the North Korean communist Kim Il Sung, attacked the south area directed by the nationalist Syngman Rhee and he seized Seoul in 1950.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Latin America and Africa in the Cold War</title>
      <link>/article/political/africa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 00:31:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/article/political/africa/</guid>
      <description>Crisis of the Congo The Congo Crisis was a period of political conflict in the Republic of Congo (today D.R. of Congo) in the timespan between 1960 – 1965. It was not only a civil war but also a proxy conflict of the Cold War, involving the Soviet Union and the UN/USA. The region was especially interesting for the two superpowers because it was very rich in natural resources such as Uranium.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pop culture (music)</title>
      <link>/article/social/popculture/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 00:31:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/article/social/popculture/</guid>
      <description>Culture in the Eastern spheres of Europe was often under strict governmental control. Pro-communist ideals were encouraged and anti-communist ideals were suppressed. This divide was most evident in Soviet-sphere music. In the USSR for example, the government encouraged the population to listen to traditional Russian Folk music, such as the song Katuschka which was covered by several different artists in many different languages. It eventually became one of the most famous communist partisan anthems along with “Bella Ciao”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Propaganda and censorship</title>
      <link>/article/social/propagandacensorship/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 00:31:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/article/social/propagandacensorship/</guid>
      <description>Picture 1: Stalin spreading communism all over the world https://sk.pinterest.com/pin/575897871091961023/ (Source    )  During the Cold War the United States as well as the Soviet Union tried to influence their people in believing in their current system and defame the enemy´s system. Especially in the USSR, which was a dictatorship, the state censored system-critical writings because they feared the people would question the political system. System-critical writers and were seen as a danger and were persecuted, imprisoned or worse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Religion</title>
      <link>/article/social/religion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 00:31:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/article/social/religion/</guid>
      <description>The fact that religion played a significant role in the Cold War might seem self-evident, given the atheistic nature of communism and the powerful influence of Christianity on the lives of millions of people on both sides of the Iron Curtain - no doubt that the governments of communist countries saw Christianity as a threat and responded accordingly. After World War II, the Catholic Church, aided by the CIA, persuaded the Italian electorate to vote for anti-communist parties, thus preventing the most popular party, the communist, from taking the power in Italy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Space Race</title>
      <link>/article/social/spacerace/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 00:31:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/article/social/spacerace/</guid>
      <description>During the time of the Cold War the USSR and USA competed in every possible way for example in the Space Race. The USSR had a head start with the launch of the first satellite Sputnik 1 in 1957; this was followed by sending the first creature (Laika, a dog) into space.
However the dog died two hours after launch. The USA only experienced failures until their first successful launch of Explorer 1 in 1958, shortly after the establishment of NASA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sport</title>
      <link>/article/social/sports/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 00:31:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/article/social/sports/</guid>
      <description>The Chess Championships of 1972 A notable occasion in the history of Cold War sports were the momentous Chess Championships of 1972. This event was a perfect example of the superpower rivalry, and has even been referred to as the ‘Match of the Century’. Sports during the Cold War were not only a test of strength, but of mind, and chess was the ultimate test of intelligence. What was especially interesting about these championships was the match between the USA and USSR, or more specifically, between challenger Bobby Fischer, and defending champion Boris Spassky.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uprising in Hungary, Czechoslovakia &amp; Poland</title>
      <link>/article/political/uprising/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 00:31:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/article/political/uprising/</guid>
      <description>Uprisings in Czechoslovakia Czechoslovakia was a part of the Soviet block from 1948 to 1989. The rule of the Communist party started with the Victorious February (1948) and end Velvet Revolution (November 1989).
 Picture 1 (Source    )  In the first election (May 26, 1946) the Communist party won and achieved the majority in parliament. Moreover, they also completely controlled the police. In protest most non-communist politicians resigned including president Beneš (February 20, 1948), Gottwald took his place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vietnam</title>
      <link>/article/political/vietnam/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 00:31:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/article/political/vietnam/</guid>
      <description>credit: https://fontawesome.comlicense: https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/ The Vietnam War was a long, costly and divisive conflict that pitted the communist government of North Vietnam against South Vietnam and its principal ally, the United States. The conflict was intensified by the ongoing Cold War between the United States and the Soviet Union. More than 3 million people (including over 58,000 Americans) were killed in the Vietnam War, and more than half of the dead were Vietnamese civilians.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>