<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home Page on Exploring the Cold War</title>
    <link>http://example.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home Page on Exploring the Cold War</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Mar 2018 00:33:20 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://example.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Berlin wall and reunification</title>
      <link>http://example.org/political/berlin-wall/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 00:31:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/political/berlin-wall/</guid>
      <description>After the war: After World War II Germany was divided into four occupation zones. There was a British, a French and an American part in the west and a Soviet part in the east. In 1949 the western occupation zones were merged to the Federal Republic of Germany (FRG). In the same year the USSR founded the German Democratic Republic (GDR) in the east of Germany.
The western part of Germany had a great development during the 1950s and 1960s known as &amp;ldquo;Wirtschaftswunder&amp;rdquo; (economic miracle).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vietnam</title>
      <link>http://example.org/political/vietnam/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Mar 2018 00:31:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/political/vietnam/</guid>
      <description>credit: https://fontawesome.comlicense: https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/ The Vietnam War was a long, costly and divisive conflict that pitted the communist government of North Vietnam against South Vietnam and its principal ally, the United States. The conflict was intensified by the ongoing Cold War between the United States and the Soviet Union. More than 3 million people (including over 58,000 Americans) were killed in the Vietnam War, and more than half of the dead were Vietnamese civilians.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Espionage</title>
      <link>http://example.org/social/espionage/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 23:47:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/social/espionage/</guid>
      <description>The Cold War is often considered the golden age of espionage, a time when the United States and Soviet Union, used all available tools to uncover each other’s secrets by operating with great secrecy and living double lives so they can infiltrate enemy governments. They certainly spent large amounts of money recruiting, training and outfitting spies and agents. The purpose of espionage was to collect information about the enemy, their army and technical abilities, their actions and intentions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>