<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Socials on Exploring the Cold War</title>
    <link>/next/article/social/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Socials on Exploring the Cold War</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 00:31:13 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/next/article/social/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Counter culture</title>
      <link>/next/article/social/counterculture/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 00:31:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/next/article/social/counterculture/</guid>
      <description>Vietnam became important to the Eastern and western blocs, the east wanted to win more communist satellite states and the west feared a communist revolt. The US supported South Vietnam with equipment and advise. This proxy war, which was typical of the Cold War, became almost like a conflict between the Soviet Union and US. Images and news from the war, for example the “Napalm Girl”, could now be seen on televisions across the world, they shocked people and many became opposed to what was happening.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pop culture (musics)</title>
      <link>/next/article/social/popculture/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 00:31:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/next/article/social/popculture/</guid>
      <description>Culture in the Eastern spheres of Europe was often under strict governmental control. Pro-communist ideals were encouraged and anti-communist ideals were suppressed. This divide was most evident in Soviet-sphere music. In the USSR for example, the government encouraged the population to listen to traditional Russian Folk music, such as the song Katuschka which was covered by several different artists in many different languages. It eventually became one of the most famous communist partisan anthems along with “Bella Ciao”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Propaganda and censorship</title>
      <link>/next/article/social/propagandacensorship/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 00:31:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/next/article/social/propagandacensorship/</guid>
      <description>Picture 2: Stalin spreading communism all over the world https://sk.pinterest.com/pin/575897871091961023/   During the Cold War the United States as well as the Soviet Union tried to influence their people in believing in their current system and defame the enemy´s system. Especially in the USSR, which was a dictatorship, the state censored system-critical writings because they feared the people would question the political system. System-critical writers and were seen as a danger and were persecuted, imprisoned or worse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Religion</title>
      <link>/next/article/social/religion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 00:31:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/next/article/social/religion/</guid>
      <description>The fact that religion played a significant role in the Cold War might seem self-evident, given the atheistic nature of communism and the powerful influence of Christianity on the lives of millions of people on both sides of the Iron Curtain - no doubt that the governments of communist countries saw Christianity as a threat and responded accordingly. After World War II, the Catholic Church, aided by the CIA, persuaded the Italian electorate to vote for anti-communist parties, thus preventing the most popular party, the communist, from taking the power in Italy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Space Race</title>
      <link>/next/article/social/spacerace/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 00:31:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/next/article/social/spacerace/</guid>
      <description>During the time of the Cold War the USSR and USA competed in every possible way for example in the Space Race. The USSR had a head start with the launch of the first satellite Sputnik 1 in 1957; this was followed by sending the first creature (Laika, a dog) into space.
However the dog died two hours after launch. The USA only experienced failures until their first successful launch of Explorer 1 in 1958, shortly after the establishment of NASA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sport</title>
      <link>/next/article/social/sports/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 00:31:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/next/article/social/sports/</guid>
      <description>The Chess Championships of 1972 A notable occasion in the history of Cold War sports were the momentous Chess Championships of 1972. This event was a perfect example of the superpower rivalry, and has even been referred to as the ‘Match of the Century’. Sports during the Cold War were not only a test of strength, but of mind, and chess was the ultimate test of intelligence. What was especially interesting about these championships was the match between the USA and USSR, or more specifically, between challenger Bobby Fischer, and defending champion Boris Spassky.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>